[Music]
[Applause]
i first posted about the bc ladder
in november of 2018 but we had been
doing it at glute lab for quite a while
my trainers sterner and bryce came up
with this as a burnout to throw in at
the end of the workout and my clients
loved it like loved it what you're gonna
do is put a glute loop
around the knees and we start out with a
small level one
a small regular gets the job done here's
how it's done
you do 12 bridges 12 abductions
then eleven and eleven ten ten nine nine
eight eight all the way down to one
you're gonna do the bridges at the
bottom of the rep but an alternative way
is to do them while you're at the top
i don't prefer that way but some of my
clients like that more so ryan is gonna
lay down
get herself in her preferred bridge
position
and from here she's going to push the
knees out
okay that's where she remains throughout
the whole ladder okay
go for it 12 bridges one faster two
three four five six
seven eight nine ten
eleven twelve now at the bottom twelve
abductions
one two three four notice how she's
rolling to the lateral edges of her feet
okay now eleven bridges are eleven
bridges go for it one
two three four five six
seven eight nine 10
11 okay 11 abductions
5 6 7 8 9 10
11. okay now 10 go for it
one two three four
five six seven eight
nine ten okay ten abduction two
three four five six seven eight nine ten
eleven okay was that ten okay
now we're going nine nine okay she's
already starting to feel the burn
i probably shouldn't raya's never done
this i probably should have started off
at 10.
uh but she'll get it done and we might
have to
suffer through it okay six
seven eight nine okay all right
burning all right let's go for it eight
eight
four five six seven
eight okay eight abduction i just put my
hand here so she doesn't slide back i'm
blocking her shoulders so she can't move
backwards okay
okay seven okay two
three four five six
seven one two
okay okay now six okay go one
two three four five
six one two
three four five six okay five five
one two three four
five one two three
four five okay four and four
one two three
four one two three four
okay one
two three one two
three okay
one two one
two okay one
one okay how you feel
i feel bad yeah she's burning okay i'll
help you sit up
okay in retrospect i should have started
ray off at 10 reps
and worked her down but she does a
different burnout all the time the band
see the hip abduction burn out so i
thought she'd be prepared for this but
it's a different drill
now you will notice yourself develop you
know more endurance for this very
rapidly so
let's say you start at 10 or even 8
you'll work your way up eventually
you'll be getting 12. and my more
advanced clients were getting 15. i
think someone might have gotten 20 at
some point but that was after like
a couple months of doing them all the
time but i like 12 and down i don't
think the goal is to you know
drive for six months from now being able
to do 30 or something like that just
keep it at 12 or low if
it's easy go 15 on down and i recommend
you throw this in two times a week
not every single week do it for a few
weeks in a row then revisit it
throughout the year a couple times
okay that is the bc ladder now you know
if you like this video make sure you
give it a thumbs up definitely leave me
a comment especially after you've given
it a try
and please make sure you're subscribed
to my channel i've got a lot more to
come
in 2021 i did make a pdf for you that
illustrates the protocol so just click
on the link in the description
and you can download that pdf anything
else okay
good all right let's go eat now if this
video intrigued you
and you would like to train under my
system using my principles
then i invite you to click on the link
below and subscribe to booty by brett
and join the thousands of other happy
members who are seeing amazing results